so we have seen that when Computing the
ILP we completely ignore false
dependencies among data dependencies and
only consider true or flow or read after
write data
dependencies so ILP really only looks at
those data dependencies but there are
two other types of dependencies in
addition to data dependencies there are
structural dependencies and control
dependencies how do they affect ILP and
the answer is that first of all when
looking at ILP there are no structural
dependencies structural dependencies
occur when we don't have enough Hardware
to do things in the same cycle when
Computing the ILP we are assuming ideal
hardware and as part of being ideal it
has no structural dependencies meaning
any instruction that could possibly
execute in the same cycle will execute
in that cycle and not have to wait on
some resource like for example there
being only one Adder so we can do only
one add in a cycle we can assume that we
have an infinite number of adders so if
we want to do an ad we do it for control
dependencies we assume that we have
perfect same cycle Branch prediction
meaning that branches are predicted in
the same cycle in which we fetch them so
we see all the correct instructions
after the branch in the same cycle in
which we see a branch let's see an
example of this where we have a program
that has a flow dependence and also an
output dependence and then we have a
branch that has a flow dependence on R1
and branches to label if the condition
is satisfied otherwise continues on and
then after the branch in the program we
have an instruction and at the label we
have another instruction so now let's
see how we compute ILP here and these
are again Cycles so what happens is in
the first cycle we can definitely do
this we cannot do them all in the first
cycle because it it depends on the ad so
we will have to wait until the second
cycle to do it the branch can actually
not be done until the third cycle
because that's where we compare this now
let's say that this branch is actually
taken what we can assume is that
although the branch cannot execute until
the third cycle from the beginning since
we started fetching the program we knew
what the branch is going to do so we
knew that the branch is going to go to
the label and thus this instruction
because it has no data dependencies on
any other instruction will actually
execute in the first cycle although it
has a control dependence so as you can
see not only are control dependencies
not resulting in any delays after the
branch
happens actually we are assuming perfect
Branch
prediction and that means that this
branch is predicted even before it's
executed so that we can just do
dependent instructions
pretty much we can completely ignore
control dependencies the branch acts as
an instruction that simply produces no
results so it eventually has to execute
but it has really no impact as far as
delaying other instructions is concerned
so in this case not only does the
multiply instruction execute even before
the branch on which it has a control
dependence executes also the
instructions that is small will feed
values to can execute before the branch
so pretty much a branch itself might be
delayed because of true dependencies but
its control dependencies on that branch
have absolutely no impact on what the
ILP will be because we are assuming
perfect Branch piction where all the
branches in the program are perfectly
predicted in the same cycle as soon as
we begin fetching the program and from
the beginning of the program we knew
exactly which instructions will execute
so that we can just do them according to
data dependencies